Today on the podcast, I sat down with Yuval Roiz and Eric Saraneki, the founders of Digital
Asset. Digital Asset was founded in 2014 and has been a leading company in the institutional
blockchain market, building on the Canton Network. In this conversation, we discussed the origins of
Digital Asset, the age old debate of permissionless versus permission blockchains, the importance of
on-chain privacy, and what's ahead for the Canton Network public blockchain. I think you'll enjoy
this one. So without further ado, here is my conversation with Yuval and Eric.
Yuval and Eric, thanks
so much for joining us today on the podcast. Excited to talk more about Digital Asset and
Canton. Yeah, great to have you, man. I think a good place to start is just who are you,
what are you guys building? And I think a lot of people have heard your names throughout the
industry and would love to just get a little bit of the background. Thanks, man. Thanks for
having us. So I'm Eric. I'm one of the co-founders at Digital Asset. We've been at this coming up
in 11 years in August. It's been quite a journey. Prior to that, I spent about a decade at DRW.
I helped get Cumberland off the ground in 13 when I've been in the crypto space for a while.
I'm really focused on making sure that our network go-to-market motion is a robust motion,
that it's pulling in people from Treadfy and crypto-native and finding really strong utility
points and crossover opportunities for those participants. Similar background to Eric,
been close to a decade at DRW and Citadel before, and both Eric and I left DRW to start this company.
My job here, beyond just running the businesses, is convincing the market why we have been
consistently doing things different than the rest of public permissionless chains.
I love it. And we're definitely going to get into that. Before we get into the
private versus public and how that is all unfolded over the years, what was the original
premise for the business? You guys were just super early to blockchains and crypto,
and what made it exciting enough to actually start a company here for you?
I think it's easy probably to say it 10 years after the fact. It all got better and better
from a messaging perspective. But I think that if DeFi is an inspiration to anyone,
I think that the reason why DeFi is so exciting is that you can process financial transactions
at a marginal cost that effectively is zero in order to bring new products, new services,
where in DeFi, doing that requires strategic partnerships, really a very well thought of
business case. You need to calculate the costs. And really doing these types of partnerships
is very expensive and hard because of the costs associated with it. And the reason why I say
that is the inspiration is because when we started Digital Asset, a recurring theme throughout the
10 years have been, how can we bring commerce or financial transactions to all happen natively on
chain? The thesis was not just that you could reduce a lot of costs that exist today in Trefi,
and as a result make businesses more profitable is we believe and we can talk about a few examples
that once you actually bring the books and records to be natively on chain,
I think the marginal cost of creating new products and new business ideas effectively
becomes financially feasible, which today is just not. So I would say that that really was the
motivation to say that I could say it as clearly as I'm saying it right now 10 years ago would
not be true, but I would say that it is a recurring theme throughout the life of the company.
Bringing institutional processes and opportunities and new businesses
into these public networks has been a motivation for us from the very beginning.
In the early days, it's so funny to think back on what this looked like in
2015 when you guys were getting going because you had a number of competitors that don't exist
anymore that were selling private blockchains in the context of Bitcoin is not going to be around,
it's not going to be a thing, and you have this choice between public or private. And
there just wasn't a lot of nuance in the conversation. You guys have always been really
nuanced around the role of public, the role of privacy, the role of
how these systems need to touch institutions. So maybe you could just talk a little bit about
that and how you think about the narratives of privacy and private chains versus public chains.
First of all, this whole public versus private is a bit silly because even chains that others
would consider to be fully public permissionless are not truly fully permissionless in the sense that
you need to get agreement from the foundation to become a validator. In some of the chains,
you need to be a multimillionaire to be a validator. What are the lines that blur between
fully public permissionless to private? And really the way I think about it is when this
technology was introduced and people got excited about it, if you wanted to bring institutional
players to it, they had some concerns about are they going to be participating in illicit activity
or in activity that they have no control of. Which generally speaking, even if it's not illicit
activity, is very challenging. In my opinion, it made sense in the early days, no different than
the internet in the early days where you actually could share your information. You started with
the internet and you had a much more controlled environment in which you said, even if I leaked
information, I'm not necessarily okay, but it wouldn't be a disaster if it happened within
this closed network. I think that some of the large scale enterprises were more comfortable
testing the technology within something that is akin to a private network. And again, that private
network doesn't necessarily mean that you even have privacy. And if you use Beisu today,
which is a private ledger, you still don't have privacy within a Beisu network. And I still think
that banks are more comfortable using Beisu, because at least they know we are participating with a
group of peers that we do business with on a day to day basis. So I think the early days were much
more about controlling the environment, not necessarily having a strict definition of what
is public permissionless versus private. It was more about working only with peers that you had
control of defining that. For us, this is why I give this example of Beisu. Again, I go to the
previous topic of how do you have books and records on chain? For us, it didn't really matter. Are you
in a private network, a public network? If you want large scale institutions to participate at scale,
privacy to us was a must have. And it wasn't something that we could give up. We worked on
the technology from the ground up where we said, rather than having just a ledger that has one
privacy model, and you need to figure out how you work within that one privacy model,
we should give the application creators the flexibility to define what are the privacy
boundaries, what are the control boundaries, and what are the access boundaries, as you would have
in most applications on the internet, and then be able to deploy it on the same network as everyone
else. We started with a much more controlled environment. So in 2020, the first version of
Canton was introduced, and you could deploy it really more as a private network. And as we were
developing the technology and getting more and more comfortable, we will be able to have
some security privacy control have all the requirements needed in order to develop it or
launch it as a fully public permissionless network. We just went towards that in middle of last year.
We had the first version of fully public Canton launch.
I'd like to ask, in the nuance category here, what's the most successful public permissionless
network in the world? It may be a trick question. Your mind goes to Bitcoin, but I guess you would
say Linux or something. How do you answer that? I like to point to the internet. Some good answers
I've heard are like the US dollar. I think that that's a really nice answer too. The scale of the
internet dwarfs what we've been able to achieve in the Bitcoin need ecosystems. And I think it has
all the characteristics of what you've all just said, which is it's a public permissionless ecosystem.
But if you're a participant in it, you determine the terms under which you participate. Am I running
a NAP? I can be wide open and everything's accessible, or I can have really strong gates.
Am I providing some services? I can have it available to anybody, or I can determine who I
interact with. In the end, there wasn't one model that won everything on the internet. We have a
super heterogeneous ecosystem. So to pretend that everything is going to be fully public, fully
decentralized, and that's the only way that you'll be able to succeed, I think it just closes the
door on a whole area of experimentation and use cases that clearly don't benefit from that. And
even the things that have been runaway successes in these public networks like stablecoins,
you have decentralized validation of an asset that the issuer can take back at any time.
It's almost a contradiction in the tools versus the outcome. And so just acknowledging
these contradictions and dropping the pretense and the religion about what it means to use
public network really opens up the design space of the types of things and the tools you can give
to the people that would join the network to find that sweet spot that works for them. Because
ultimately if it's not value for them and it's not value for their investors or their counter parties
or their customers, none of this is going to grow. It just kind of becomes an echo chamber.
We wanted to make sure that we gave everybody the tools to figure out the right level of all
those different levers for them to solve a problem and achieve an outcome.
This was brought to life for me and really where I started to understand what you guys are doing at
a more granular level is when you started to tell me about some of the use cases around
collateral management and how your customers were using the network. So maybe you could talk a little
bit about that use case around collateral and why this setup is optimal for that use case.
What's really interesting about collateral is today it's a very low velocity project. It's the
backbone of why you can trade your leveraging assets. It's what gives you your margin ability.
It's what allows you to settle. It's what allows you to de-risk your counterparty risk. But then
we really only have the facilities to move them efficiently maybe once a day during business
days. And markets are increasingly 24 by 7. Markets are increasingly international. They're
interconnected. And the limiting factor today is really balance sheet and collateral efficiency.
There's somewhere in the neighborhood of 230 trillion dollars of eligible collateral in the
world. I think we use barely 10 percent of it in the workflows that we have today. People are
balance sheet constrained and simultaneously significantly underutilizing the collateral
that is available, not using it at a velocity that's going to actually de-risk the process.
You know, if I have collateral on a Friday, someone goes bankrupt on a Sunday and I walk
in Monday, I'm walking into fire sale risk. So just being able to take these things and say,
great, I want to do a variation margin cycle with my counterparty every two hours. You're
taking massive amounts of risk off the table. And in order to do that, you have to have a ledger
that allows you to move these assets in a safe and secure way with high velocity, with high
certainty, but also with privacy. Because when you're thinking about a derivatives position,
that variation margin is giving away a lot of information about, well, maybe I'm short deltas
or I'm short volatility, and that's why I'm net delivering on this movement. And you can start to
learn a lot about someone's position by just watching the money movements. And then that
can turn into market manipulation problems that can turn into market interference problems.
And ultimately, what that means is that I think that the whole crypto ecosystem is undersized
because when you start to get into those transactions big enough that people would want
to take advantage of that information, you're going off chain, you're going bilateral,
you're going away from these automated systems, and you're effectively just entering back into
the very low velocity high counterparty risk environment that we had before. Without privacy,
without the mobility of these assets, you can't really fundamentally change the backbone of
markets, which is how you settle and manage this risk. Cantons really design from the ground up to
support those types of capabilities. So whether it's treasuries or hero bonds or guilds or money
market funds or wrapped crypto or stable coins, all those things move with the same velocity
and getting the liquidity figured out between them and being able to post all of them and
substitute all of them and find the cheapest thing to deliver is a killer use case for blockchain.
And then without privacy, you'll just never get to the level of scale
and adoption to break out of the casino. That's what we're really excited about. It's just to
demonstrate how we can do this crossover. We can solve problems in crypto, but just as equally,
if not more importantly, can solve problems in Treadfy that have the same characteristics.
I think for those who have participated in crypto till the year of 2014-15, if you wanted to trade
in multiple crypto exchanges, you had to over collateralize all of your accounts because you
couldn't capture the opportunity fast enough by wiring money from one exchange to another.
And then Ethereum showed up and then Tether showed up. And voila, suddenly the efficiency in crypto
just blew up. And I think you could actually see that in markets from volumes,
that suddenly I could actually manage my capital much more efficiently because now I can move US
dollars all over the world 24-7. Now in crypto, they accepted that that happens without privacy.
That was just a given. I actually think that the same phenomena exists in Treadfy markets,
but at 100x the size of the markets. So imagine if a similar phenomena were to happen in Treadfy
by mobilizing collateral 24-7 to what you saw in crypto when stablecoins were introduced.
That to me is what gets me excited is I just see that paradigm shift and that definitely
can exist. I mean, just recently, you start seeing exchanges talking about 24-5 or 24-7.
Well, how are they going to do that? Currently, the solution is over collateralize all of your
accounts, but that's not capital efficient. If you think about interest rates where they are,
massive movements in the market right now, you cannot capture all of these opportunities unless
you have the balance sheet to do that. I think the opportunity here is dramatic,
and I will add to the point about privacy. I don't think that Treadfy organizations
would accept to do that on their Treadfy activity without privacy and crypto, they kind of accept it.
The interesting thing is since we introduced Canton, it's now even the crypto native players
that are coming and saying, hey, how do we move these assets with privacy because we don't enjoy
people front-running us because they keep on watching all of our wallets and all of these
non-privacy chains and people do front-run them. It's interesting to see that even now,
the institutional crypto players are very focused on privacy and figuring out how they can obfuscate
their activity. It's interesting because in crypto, it was almost just that the technology
for privacy didn't exist in the early days. There's a path dependency here, whereas if you could have
done this out of the gate, if Bitcoin had some privacy layer on top of it, it very well could
have been the way that that market evolved. It's interesting that it didn't have privacy out of
the gate, and so people are adapted to it. Later, entrepreneurs like yourselves come across and
make it better. It's interesting to watch from the outside in.
I really like how Zuko talks about this. In the early days, he used to always talk with Satoshi
about how the transparency was a major bug and a major flaw and that it was very hard for them to
achieve their ideal without it. Then somewhere in like 14 through 18, transparency became the
selling point. The bug became the feature. I think people are coming back to realization that the
transparency is a major flaw in design. The thing is, it's going to be very difficult for people to
pivot out of that because so much of the design of what they've built relies upon the full transparency
of the system. Everybody built their integration, assuming they have access to all the data.
Everybody built everything that they do in these ecosystems, the dApps. Everything is
more than just let's try to bolt on some privacy preservation. It really leads to a fundamental
rethink about what it means to be connected to these ecosystems and how you interact with them.
Another point that you're seeing as very popular now is the conflation between zero knowledge
and privacy. Maybe that's an important thing to distinguish is that we don't consider zero
knowledge as a privacy solution. It's an anonymity solution. It's a way to obfuscate the inputs from
everyone involved in the transaction. Again, if you bring it back to, I give this example, imagine
you had a zero knowledge algorithm called San Bankman Freed, which you just give it collateral,
and San Bankman Freed tells you, great, we have the collateral. It's here. It's with us. Until you
have the market meltdown, and you need to call on that collateral, and then you find out that there
was a bug into zero knowledge, and the collateral was actually never there. To us, that is not
privacy, that if anything opens the door for systemic risk within the system because we know
there's always bugs. I think one of the critical things that we've been thinking about is privacy
is how do you make sure that only the stakeholders to the transaction have full visibility into what's
on the ledger, where those that are not stakeholders to the transactions just actually don't know
set activity have happened on the ledger. I think that that's a very big difference. I think the
reason why ZKPs are now being pushed as a privacy solution is because it's a nice bolt-on
on ledgers that haven't thought of privacy from first principles as like an anchor tenant in
their design. It's much more comfortable now to add zero knowledge as an afterthought.
To bring this to life maybe on how this would work on the chain itself, say I am moving treasury
collateral over to you guys, what would the public see on the blockchain itself when I'm making that
collateral movement? They wouldn't. This is really the nice thing about Canton is that you could
actually have two different applications that have very different privacy models. Let's just imagine
that Matt you're my prime broker, I'm your client, and you send me variation margin calls throughout
the day. We decided that my activity with my prime broker is fully private to us. We don't want anyone
else in the world to know about the margin calls, but we do know let's just imagine that we have a
stable coins. In the case of Circle on Canton it will be with privacy, but let's imagine that Circle
wanted to issue it very similar to how stable coins have been working on other chains where
everybody gets to see everyone's account balances in a pseudo-anonymous manner. The nice thing in
Canton is that you could actually compose a transaction of two applications that have very
different privacy models, still compose a transaction. Imagine you gave me a transaction
which is you created a variation margin request and now I want to fund it with USDC. You and I, Matt,
will actually see an atomic transaction between me satisfying the variation margin versus the USDC
moving between the two wallets. Eric, who's not part of that transaction, would only see USDC
moving between two wallets. He wouldn't know for what reason. Why? Because he's not a stakeholder
to the crime brokerage transaction. And that's really, I think, the power of Canton is the world
is not homogeneous. It actually has the capability of composing multiple applications that have very
different privacy settings without leaking information between them. The way that Canton
works dynamically calculates who are the stakeholders to the transaction and it knows how to have
effectively consensus across only those stakeholders. And you can have, like I said,
multiple levels of privacy. I can think of so many examples where having that feature in the
stablecoin market would make the stablecoin market better and larger. Think about payroll
use cases and regular vendor payments that you wouldn't want fully disclosed. Just shocking
that the stablecoin market has gotten as large as it has without this. I totally agree. I mean,
listen, we have customers that are doing life insurance natively on chain. They actually do
not have any other system of record beyond Canton. And the reason why they got comfortable
is because of the security and privacy features of Canton. And now they are exactly talking to us,
hey, how can we integrate something like stablecoins to actually process some of the transactions?
And the reason is because they can actually do that with privacy. So they totally see the value
of, hey, if I have these assets natively on chain, I can securitize these products much easier.
I can process transactions. I can process payments related to them. But I'm not sacrificing any of
my fiduciary duties to my clients and customers. In the early days, I'm sure you were going to a
lot of institutions and they were just trying to figure out what the heck is Bitcoin and explain
to me blockchain technology. These days, maybe some of that's still going on. I suspect it probably
is at some institutions, but then you have other institutions that are mentioning Canton on earnings
calls. It's a very interesting market to observe from my side where the discrepancy is crazy here.
So what does it look like for you guys when you show up at an institution and how are you talking
about the various business cases? I don't know if it's because of fatigue or because I find it to be
more productive to not talk about blockchain. It's incredible when you explain to people, for
example, we do this project with iCapital, putting private equity on chain and efficiencies, the DeFi
opportunities that now you can effectively encumber these assets to get lending against LP holdings
and things like that. It's amazing when you go to customers and you understand and appreciate
their business and you understand where they make money and where they spend dollars.
And you don't come to them with a brave world kind of vision of how they need to change everything
that they're doing. And you're just saying, look, we've done AXYZ with these type of customers that
are very similar to what you do and look at the result that they have. I just find those conversations
to be much easier and much more productive. And it's not about my blockchain is bigger or
better or faster or cheaper than others. It does eventually translate into hard questions
about privacy. I can tell you when I had recently a meeting with a very impressive woman at a
clearinghouse, a very important clearinghouse, and she dismissed the whole art of the possible and
everything. She was like, you want to talk to me about collateral? Tell me how you perfect title.
And I love that because she kind of got to like, don't tell me about I can move assets
between wallets fast enough. If you really want to talk collateral, it means that, you know,
what is the meaning of perfecting a title? What does it mean to be bankruptcy remote?
And if you can convince me that you've thought about those things and your technology can
solve for that, then we'll move to the next phase. So again, it's kind of a very similar angle that
what has worked really well in the last few years is talking about business outcomes without having
to say, hey, you need to reset everything you know about your world. You need to kind of throw away
your 20 years of experience. And we're just going to do everything fresh from the ground up.
When you don't talk like that, you talk about incremental gains that are much more
anchored in reality. It ends up being a much more fruitful conversation.
They get very excited by the tale of opportunity. That's what I think has changed a lot in the
past five years is that some things have had good success. And so they can see how things can get
beyond that initial phase. So I would say that the body language is a lot more leaning forward
than defensive. But to Yuval's point, if it's not about how it's going to transform their
business to be safer, cheaper, make them more money, make their customers more money, it doesn't
really matter what's under the hood. So being outcome driven and focus on it and then making
sure that the tech doesn't run into all the reasons you're going to get vetoed. It's still a
process. It's still a conversation, but people are more inclined to want to find a positive outcome
and an answer to move forward than they were maybe five years ago. But
you're still going to go through the exact same vetting process.
It's really impressive what you guys have built from an ecosystem perspective. If you just take
the lens that this is not necessarily always just a technology problem. It's ultimately like a network
effect financial services landscape that only works if a lot of different counterparties are all
on the same network. So how have you guys thought about crafting that network as you've grown the
organization over time and trying to figure out the use cases that have what I would call a minimum
viable ecosystem? They don't work if just one or two firms get on board? You'd be surprised though
how often you can find an entry point where it is enough that there's one or two firms.
And so it's really useful to find those and start. I mean, as an example, the repo project that we
have with Broadridge, we started with Intra company. So the London versus the French versus the New
York part of the organization or the deposit tokens that are doing well with transfer pricing and
internal treasury management. Sometimes one's enough because within an organization there's
an ecosystem already. So finding an entry point is really important. But then to really accelerate
that and turn it into something meaningful, it's about finding those early connections into something
else. It's more important to find the connections to other applications than it is to have more
users in your application. My example that I like to talk a lot about is if you think about
capital markets, love them or hate them, they sit underneath all the crypto native products that we
rely on the most. When we talk about a stablecoin, where is the stable, it's sitting in treasuries,
it's at bony, it's in the repo and reverse repo market, it's holding money market funds.
So you have a fundamentally crypto native asset that is buoyed by the strength and power and
trustworthiness of capital markets. But it also means that if they're accessing those capital
markets in traditional ways, that they're held back by whatever those current shortcomings are.
Cool, stablecoin, you've actually only solved a portion of the problem, being able to instantly
create or redeem that 24 hours a day, being able to deliver treasuries, not just money through the
Fedwire, being able to face them in repo, 24 by seven repo, intraday repo, over the weekend repo,
custom tenor and term, all that sort of stuff. That's where we look for the first connections.
You've solved an immediate problem by issuing an asset. Now, where can you use that as collateral?
Or can I compose that with a cash movement? Or can I automate some of the life cycle events
through this other system? And that secondary app connection is where things really take off,
because that's where we think that blockchain really is the technological innovation is in the
composability area. Earlier, we were talking about private blockchains. The reason we've always
been allergic to getting classified as a private blockchain is because you're throwing composability
up the window, which is the big opportunity here. So we've always been focused on making sure that
no matter how we've come to market, no matter where we start, no matter how narrow that entry point is,
composability is a short-term goal and a technological possibility because of what's
built into Canton. If you go again back to the previous question about what we're talking to
customers, I think for us, the name of the chain Canton, why Canton? Canton is really,
first, our team is in Switzerland who built it, and this is more of a tribute to them. But it's
also, if you think about Switzerland as really a federation of cantons, they all kind of have their
nuance, different tax, different language, different rules, but they all interoperate under
Switzerland. The goal of the network is really to create user experiences if I'm connected to one
network, but really under the hood, it's many, many cantons that all interoperate with one another.
The reason I bring that up is because when you think about the beachheads that we've done,
in many cases, they were kind of a closed network that solved a very specific problem for that network.
But because they all build on the same protocol, eventually they all come together. So now
USDC comes to the network. Oh, wow. All of the cantons that are just doing transactions on the
asset side now can compose transactions to get rid of their traditional payment provider
to settle the cash leg using USDC. We have a life insurance company. They were solving life
insurance and annuities business. But now we have private assets that exist on cantons like
private credit, private equity. Guess what? You can encumber those assets into a whole life platform.
And I can keep on giving you examples, securitization of mortgages, horse racing,
physical mad gas, collateral, security lending. All of those beachheads were solving very specific
problems. But eventually the long-term strategy was as long as they can hold on their two feet
for long enough, eventually as the technology becomes more and more popular, you are starting
now to see these connections between them. We've done repo and canton. Guess what? Now when you have
US treasuries or Euro bonds and guilds on canton, well, now suddenly a stablecoin provider can do
24 by 7 repo to do a 24 by 7 create redeem of a stablecoin. The long-term view was very similar
to the internet, solve an immediate efficiency within a localized network. But long-term as the
technology becomes more and more popular, you will start seeing these composable interactions
throughout the network. Yeah, it's such a great example of the intranet versus internet. And you
can see how that evolves. It's also really clear that you must be talking to a lot of different
institutions that have different pain points. Some of them are probably looking at cost savings
and others. You can just imagine new markets getting created here, where there are just
things that wouldn't otherwise be possible without a technology like this. So I want to switch gears
here a little bit just to the token itself on the canton network. So this is not a theory. You
guys have this in production. It's working today. People are on it. So maybe you could talk a little
bit about the token itself, the public network, how it works, why it matters. First of all,
maybe just about generically speaking, the token, we believe that this space have had
too many white papers selling tokens to retail. And for us, we wanted to go back
to the original thinker behind this movement who said the technology needs to prove itself.
And as a result, the token will be earned and we'll appreciate in value. So first of all,
we decided with everyone else who helped us launch the network that we're going to do a fair
launch. We didn't do a pre-mine digital asset doesn't sit on 60, 70, 80% of the token. We wanted
it to be a decentralized network and we wanted the network to gain value because it proves its
value. A lot of people in crypto thought we were stupid for doing that, but we thought it was
extremely important. Second of all, we wanted to make sure that before we list the token,
you could trade the token today, you could do secondary trades. But before we list the token,
we actually show real world utility at scale running on the network. And that is still on
track to get listed later this year. And I think we will be hopefully top 10 from dollar utility
actually on chain when we get listed. And that will be exciting. I think that when you look at
Bitcoin, it is an asset class. It's not a blockchain. It's an asset class that has a blockchain to
drive that asset class. And therefore, it makes sense for those that secure that use case to earn
all the reward. When you start thinking of smart contract chains, it's more of a platform. And we
believe that this idea that miners or validators earn all of their reward is not the right incentive
structure. Why? Because it is the builders, it's the users that actually create the value. They
think about the business models, they think about new creative ideas, they do marketing,
they go to conferences, they have meetings, they work really hard to make their DApps or
DeFi protocols a success. And I think that it is pretty odd that no one in the smart contract
chain to economics world came and said, well, if they drive all the volume and as a result,
all the fees into our networks, they deserve a big chunk of their reward. And this is not
a new concept. You have influencers, you have interchange, you have just so many different
things where there should be some kind of a shared economics with those that drive the success to
the network. So I'll leave it at that high level to let Eric kind of explain the specifics.
But it's this idea that we wanted to make sure if you come to build on Canton, if you invest
time, effort, and you become successful, we believe that a big portion of the two economics
should go your way for that investment. Very similarly, people ask me all the time, like,
you guys have been at this for over 10 years, what was the point of the coin and why the timing
on it? Timing is also a question we get a lot. And so for me, it always starts from the same place
which is about aligned incentives. What I think the crypto ecosystem has done an excellent job of
doing in the past roughly 15 years is experimenting with different incentive systems and creating
incentive systems where there are first mover advantages where technologically there may not
be network effects don't necessarily have first mover advantages. And so to be able to create
those opportunities is very important. It helps you kind of bootstrap an ecosystem. It creates
the incentive to move quicker rather than slower. It entices the more risk loving early participants.
I used to always really respect and love these crypto networks for being a really strong filter
for people that want to participate in these apps. I think that that's something that gets overlooked
a lot is you have a very active community of people that are willing to adopt the latest decks
or the latest chain or the latest lending protocol or whatever it may be. And I think a big part of
that is that the incentive structures that have been designed around these networks have encouraged
and cultivated that community. It was time to do that in Canton. I've jokingly sometimes said we
built a network the way you might have built a strip mall in the 90s anchor tenants first and
then open it up and brought it into a bigger ecosystem. And part of that was about aligning
the incentives between all the participants that would come early. So do you all point
concretely in every single block there's three tranches of mining rewards one third of all the
rewards that will ever get minted over the first 10 years of the network go to the miners which is
very small percentage as compared to other networks which generally are right around 100%.
If not 100% like we mentioned there's no pre-mine or pre-sale. So every coin that will ever come
into existence gets earned by somebody doing something. And one of those categories is being
what we call a super validator but just think of it as mining. The second category is going to users
think of it as like a transaction subsidy you know it helps cover some of your expenses of using
the chain. So the more active you are then the more of that validator reward or user reward you'll
receive. And then the preponderance of the reward 50% of all the coins that will get earned by anybody
over the first 10 years go to applications as measured by the network fees that they generate.
And this is I think relatively unheard of and the other networks I haven't seen other examples
certainly not at the scale of the reward that we've done. And in its absence what you see is a
fairly large grant ecosystem and a lot of other networks makes me uneasy uncomfortable it's just
very transactional can build very mercenary like behaviors doesn't necessarily produce the outcomes
that the chains are hoping for the communities are hoping for. And it also changes a lot you bet on
startup A but actually startup B was the winner and they went into a different ecosystem. So
what you want to do is have something that's way more responsive to how fast the ecosystem is
moving. So in canton in block zero if this one app is responsible for 35 of the network fees
generated in block one they're going to take 35% of the application reward. We think that with all
the difficulties that come in helping foster an ecosystem around that it was important to try to
do that and to try to align the network outcomes with those that are putting in the equity and the
sweat and the tears to make it happen. Time will tell if this was a better way to do things we're
pretty excited about running the experiment and creating the opportunity to try a different model
it's resonating with people a lot you see behaviors change a lot ordinarily in other networks you
get paid to stake and think about what that means behaviorally you're taking things out of
circulation and you're doing nothing and that's how you get paid and in canton it's the opposite
you have to put stuff into use to work you have to do stuff on chain to get paid and so it's really
this behavioral economics that we're trying to engender by doing rewards this way. To me the most
exciting sign actually of the tokenomics is some fairly large stratify organizations sitting with
us doing business projections based on tokenomics. I don't think I thought I would live for that day
to say that I'm sitting with some very traditional clients thinking about tokenomics models of
saying like cool I have my business model this is kind of how I price it but if I now drive
x amount of volumes into canton let's simulate the price of canton coin say that we do x amount
of the activity this is how much would be our reward this is how much we extrapolate as revenue
and these are very traditional organization. To me even the exercise is worth it.
I think it's fascinating I think you'll even have business school case studies written about this
time period in this technology because you look at how the credit card networks were built or look
at how Swift or CLS evolved and this could just be the next generation of how community owned
infrastructure ends up coming together. That's exactly it Matt what you said is literally how
I pitch sometimes this idea is the way we need to think of public network is a network owned
shared infrastructure that is decentralized and therefore if you think about this if you take
an analogy that this is a decentralized cloud or a decentralized computer and you're saying I am
driving x amount of revenue towards that well guess what I want a cut of that revenue if I'm
creating a multiple for this community based infrastructure I want my piece of flesh as a
result of that. Totally I'm super impressed with what you guys have built and we're excited to be
a part of it where can we send people that want to learn more get involved join the community
start building things on canton. The fastest way to be able to join the network is if you go to
sync.global that's the global synchronizer foundation site there is a series of links
you can follow there about getting a validator or joining the ecosystem and connecting to the network
we have a bunch of ecosystem partners that help facilitate access as well so even for someone
who's not technologically savvy they can join they can come through a wall provider they can come
through a number of different entities that support the ecosystem and you can find a healthy
list of who that is at sync.global and also at canton.network. Incredible well thanks for
joining the podcast today guys excited to monitor what happens here going forward it sounds like
there's a ton of buzz on Canton and really excited to see the use cases evolve so appreciate all
you're doing. Thank you Matt. Thanks Brett. Thanks for listening to another episode of On the Brink
with Castle Island to find out more about Castle Island visit castleisland.vc to listen to all
of our podcast episodes please go to onthebrink-podcast.com or just click on the tab in our website
thanks for listening